Filip Mareš

Mistrovská 170/18, Praha 10 mobile: +420 777 11 66 30 e-mail: maresf@gmail.com

linkedin: http://uk.linkedin.com/in/filipmares1 portfolio: http://www.filip-mares.co.uk/

date of birth: 13. 6. 1980 nationality: Czech marital status: Single

Professional Profile

Client-side web developer with a high level of industry knowledge and over 16 years experience in creating fast, standards-compliant, accessible websites and web applications using current best practises.

Interested in creating clean and highly maintainable code which works across all browsers and platforms.

Team experiences

Provided team leadership to small teams, experienced in working with cross discipline Agile teams, also in the Scrum Master role.

Portfolio

Completed work for major clients across various sectors including British Telecom, Tesco, M&S, Sony, Unilever, Lloyds TSB, Oriflame, Garanti Bank, DHL, Datart and Neoluxor.

Cycle Builds knowledge

Have developed web sites from start to finish (planning, wireframes, design, development, testing cycle, go live.)

Today

Most recently focused on Front End performance optimization, mobile development, RWD and RESS. Passionate about learning new technologies and skills in order to keep up-to-date.

Technical Skills

OO JavaScript, jQuery, Ajax, JSON, HTML5, XML, XSLT, SVG, web accessibility, cross-browser compatibility, web performance, OO CSS, LESS, web typography, mobile web, RWD, RESS, unit testing, continuous integration, source control

Other

languages: native Czech, advanced English driving licence: Groups A and B, skilled

Work Related Experience

Internet Projekt, a.s. (2012 - 2014)

Lead Front-End Developer in Internet agency

Responsibilities

- Web Development & standards establishment
- Team leading & Scrum Mastering
- Mobile development

Clients

Ministry of Finance of the Czech Republic, Senate of the Parliament of the Czech Republic, Oriflame

Silkroute UK (2011)

Front-End Developer in Worldwide provider of supply chain solutions

Responsibilities

- Web Development
- Front End Performance Optimisation
- Cross Browser Compatibility

Clients

Tesco

LBi London (2008 – 2011)

Front-End Developer in Digital Media Agency

Responsibilities

- Web Development
- Web Content Accessibility & Cross Browser Compatibility
- · Front End Performance Optimisation

Clients

BT, Lloyds TSB, M&S, Unilever, Sony, Houses of Parliament, National Grid, Barclays, F1, Garanti Bank, Tourism Ireland, Barratt Homes

Nantuko (2004 – 2008)

Lead Front-End Developer in Creative Internet Agency

Responsibilities

- Team Coordination, work redistribution and review
- Web Analytics & Strategy, Search Engine Marketing (SEO, PPC advertising & CRO)
- · Web Development

Clients

Neoluxor On-line Bookstore, DHL, Danone, Iveco, KESA Electricals - Datart, Metropole Zlicin - Centre of Fashion and Entertainment

M.P. Media s.r.o. (2001 – 2004)

Senior Front-End Developer in Publishing Company

Responsibilities

- Team Coordination, work redistribution and review
- Web Development

Projects

Internet projects supporting selling of magazines, Mobile content developing

Economy.cz (1997 – 2001)

Front-End Developer in Internet Services Company

Responsibilities

- · Web Development
- · Graphic Design

Clients

Ministry of Foreign Affairs of the Czech Republic, Dräger Safety, Ranný Architects, Asiana Global Travel Service

Education

Czech Technical University in Prague (1999 - 2002)

Faculty of Electrical Engineering

3 years studies of Programing, Mathematics, Physics and others.

Gymnázium U Libeňského zámku (1995 - 1999)

GCE level, Secondary school

Certificate of Information Technology, Mathematics, English, and Czech Language. General studies focused on Information Technology and Mathematics.